Guide to the Thom Fogarty Collection on ACT UP and AIDS Research MSS.518
Fales Library and Special Collections
Thom Fogarty Collection on ACT UP and AIDS Research
1990-1991
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fogarty, Thom
ACT UP (Organization)
MSS.518
1.75 linear feet in 1 record carton, 1 manuscript box, and 1 half manuscript box.
Thom Fogarty has been a part of New York City's Downtown theater community since the 1970s. As a dancer and choreographer Fogarty has been known for portraying theatrical characters through mimetic movements. Since 2010 he has focused more on directing and producing theater, and is currently the Artistic Director of 360repco. This collection consists of materials created and collected by Fogarty in the early 1990s documenting his direct action advocacy efforts to positively impact the lives of people with AIDS and to further legislative, scientific research, and medical treatment measures to end the disease. Materials in this collection include news articles, meeting notes, meeting agendas, and ephemera from the advocacy group AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power (ACT UP) documenting the organization's efforts to raise awareness of the AIDS pandemic both in the greater New York City area and more broadly domestically. The collection also documents medical research and drug trials, including articles on new pharmaceutical products, documentation on a 1990 Ampligen drug trial that Fogarty acted as liason for with the pharmaceutical company, and materials collected from conferences on clinical trials and developments in medial treatments that Fogarty attended.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials created and collected by Thom Fogarty in the early 1990s documenting his direct action advocacy efforts to positively impact the lives of people with AIDS and to further legislative, scientific research, and medical treatment measures to end the disease. Materials in this collection include news articles, meeting notes, meeting agendas, and ephemera from the advocacy group AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power (ACT UP) documenting the organization's efforts to raise awareness of the AIDS pandemic both in the greater New York City area and more broadly domestically. Many of these agendas and the accompanying articles were produced by the group's Media Committee. The collection also documents medical research and drug trials, including articles on new pharmaceutical products, documentation on a 1990 Ampligen drug trial that Fogarty acted as liason for with the pharmaceutical company, and materials collected from conferences on clinical trials and developments in medial treatments that Fogarty attended.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Biographical Note
Thom Fogarty has been a part of New York City's Downtown theater community since the 1970s. He earned a BFA in Dance Performance and History from Ohio State University, and was a part of both dance and theater productions from 1977 to 2010. As a dancer and choreographer Fogarty has been known for portraying theatrical characters through mimetic movements. Since 2010 he has focused more on directing and producing theater. He is currently the Artistic Director of 360repco directing non-for-profit plays from new or forgotten playwrights. During the late 1980s and early 1990s, Fogarty was an active member of ACT UP and other AIDS activist groups, attended numerous conferences on AIDS research and treatment, and participated in clinical studies, notably acting as a liaison to HEM Pharmaceuticals for their experimental studies on the drug Ampligen as a possible treatment for AIDS.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Thom Fogarty in April 2017. The accession number associated with this gift is 2017.219
Drug trials; AIDS activists -- New York (State) -- New York; AIDS (Disease) -- Government -- United States.; Pharmaceutical industry.; AIDS (Disease) -- New York (State) -- New York.; AIDS (Disease) -- Political aspects -- United States
- ACT UP Meeting Handouts, 1990-11-1991-02 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- ACT UP Media Committee, 1990-07-1990-12 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- AIDS Clinical Trials, 1991-03-1991-07 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- ATAC Confrence, 1990-11 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- ACT UP Meeting Agenda, 1990-10-1991-06 (Box 1, Folder 6-15)
- AIDS Treatment Registry, 1990-04 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- AIDS Treatment Resources, 1990-10-1990-12 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Anti-Viral Drug Advisory Committee Conference, 1991-02 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- AIDS Clinical Trials Group, 1991-03 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Countdown 18, 1990-11 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Notes on Community Research Initiative, 1990-08-1991-01 (Box 1, Folder 21-23)
- CRI Treatment and Research, 1990-05-1990-11 (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
- AIDS Treatment Activist Confrence, 1990-11-10 (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
- ACT UP Meeting Agenda, 1991-02-1991-04 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
- The Treatment and Data Digest, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
- 11th AIDS Clinical Trials Group Meeting, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
- Ampligen Trial, 1990-09-1991-02 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
- Ampligen Overview, 1990-10-09 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Ampligen Protocols, 1990-08-1990-11 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Ampligen Trials, 1990-11 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Ampligen Disclosure, 1990-11 (Box 3, Folder 10-12)